

CONTACT

+91 8867447566

✓ amarjeetkumar4all@gmail.com

Bangalore, India

SKILLS

Operating Systems

Windows Server(2012, 2016, 2019, 2022), ESXI, Linux

 Windows & VMware Administrator

AD, GPO, DNS, DHCP, Failover cluster

Data Center Administrator
 HP. Cisco UCS , Dell and IBM Servers

• Virtualization VMware, Horizon VDI

Patching Tool
 SCCM

- Azure Cloud
- Scripting Tool PowerShell
- Monitoring Tool Solarwinds, SCOM, AD Aduit

Ticketing Tool

Service Now, SC3, BMC Remedy and Jira

CERTIFICATIONS

- Azure Administrator
 AZ-104
- VMware Administrator
 VMware Certified Data Center
 Virtualization 2023

AMARJEET KUMAR

SENIOR CONSULTANT

PROFILE

Having 12 years of experience in IT Infrastructure automation and solutions. Primarily worked on Azure Cloud, Windows, and VMware platforms using PowerShell scripting and patching Windows servers and client machines using the SCCM patching tool.

WORK EXPERIENCE

T-Systems ICT PVT Ltd

Sr Consultant

December 2021 - Present

Computacenter PVT Ltd

Sr Technical Analyst

December 2020 - December 2021

Hudson Bay

Sr System Engineer

August 2018 - December 2020

Wipro Ltd

System Engineer

September 2014 - July 2018

Wipro Ltd on Payroll of Care IT solution Pvt Ltd

Technical Support Executive

July 2012 - September 2014

ROLES AND RESPONSEBILITIES

- Managing and maintaining the on-premise Windows platform, ESXI, VM Servers, and Azure cloud resources.
- Managing and troubleshooting AD, GPO, DNS, DHCP, File servers, IIS Web servers, and Failover clusters in Dev and Production environment.
- Installations of SCOM clients on servers and configure alert Mechanism in SCOM and proactive action on respective alerts.
- Managing, maintaining, and Troubleshooting VMware and Horizon VDI infrastructure.
- Managing the MS clusters and maintaining the nodes and services to maintain high availability.
- Hardware upgrade of Physical Server (HP ProLiant server, Cisco UCS server, IBM and Dell).

EDUCATION

BSc IT (Bachelor of Science in Information Technology)
Bundhelkhand University Jhansi
Year of passing 2012

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hindi

- Having experience in the upgradation of Windows server 2012 to 2016/2019/2022.
- Upgrading the Infrastructure by decommissioning the legacy servers.
- Install, configure, and maintain the virtual environment utilizing Horizon View and vCenter.
- Creating and maintaining VDI master images and installing client applications.
- Developed plans for deploying and administering virtual machines and images.
- Performing Daily VDI administration, maintenance, and upgrades including service packs, patches, hotfix, and security configuration.
- Monitor performance and ensure system availability and reliability.
- Work with the hardware vendor to isolate and resolve the issue.
- Managed snapshots, clones, and Templates during patch release and new server deployment.
- Create, manage, and maintain Group policy objects and Group policy preferences.
- Managing and maintaining DNS and DHCP server and performing administrator Tasks.
- Monitoring Domain Controller's connectivity, synchronization, and replication.
- Maintaining DC servers and performing administrator Tasks such as creation of OU, Group, and security permission. Creation/deletion/management of objects.
- Monitoring Hardware, network, storage, HA & DRS Service alert.
- Responsible for VM build and VM features like High Availability, DRS, Vmotion, Storage Vmotion, and Fault Tolerance.
- Working on Vcenter Server 6.5, 6.7, 7.0 & 8.0 for managing multiple ESXI Servers.
- Responsible for ESXI patching using update manager as per client requirement.
- Worked on P2V and V2V migration of Windows 2008 and 2012 servers using VMware Converter and PlateSpin migration tool.
- Maintaining and managing the 6000 VDI in a virtual environment utilizing VMware Horizon View.
- Performing daily VDI administration, maintenance, and upgrades including service packs, patches, hotfixes, and security configurations.
- Creation of desktop golden images for VMware horizon view composer and instant clone.
- Maintaining and managing the view composer, view connection, and view security server.
- Troubleshooting and resolving VDI issues.
- Experience in scripting language VBScript and PowerShell to automate common functions.
- Designed and developed automation scripts using PowerShell for daily System Engineering Tasks.